Today we will talk about Reliance Health
Insurance. Reliance General
Insurance has launched a plan
in the health segment, which is named Reliance
Health Infinity Plan.
Reliance Health
Infinity is being discussed a lot in the news because it has a lot of features, a lot of
flexibility, a lot of
additional benefits. Understanding its customers, they will bring
what the customers need. Accordingly,
they have given a lot of flexibility in the policy. So
today we will see about this policy, we will decode it,
understand what is included, what is
excluded, what is an additional right hand,
what is new in this policy and what
is the cost. Before starting the video, I would
like to introduce myself. My name
is Gurleen Kaur Chikku. I am a Certified
Financial Planner. I bring videos for you every week,
which makes your personal
financial life easy and happy. Let's
move towards the video. Today's product is
Reliance Health Infinity Plan. So, the
high sum assured in this plan is up to Rs 5 crore. There are more
options in this plan. There are many
options in which you get more cover,
more time and more  You
get flexibility, along with that you get unlimited
restoration and then OPD cover, three
useful add-on benefits which you
can add-on. There are also many discounts
in this policy and many
reward points, meaning if you
remain financially fit and physically fit then there are
reward points too. What did I say about
physical fit? You must have heard that if you
remain active then we
give you discount on insurance.
What is financially fit? There is a discount for financially fit as well.
If your credit score is
good then you will be given a discount.
We will see everything about it in detail in this video.
Whatever I am
telling you, stay till the end of the video.
I am sir, this video will be very interesting.
Reliance Health Infinity Plan. First let's
talk about its basics, what is the
eligibility criteria? My
entry is 91 days, maximum entry age is
65 years, child's age is 25 years. After 25 years the
child will be separated.
In the second policy, the minimum time limit is 3 years
and maximum  If the policy is worth five crore rupees, then it is a
very white choice. You have a plan
which you can take in India and your
family and it is available with you for one year, two
year and three years, you know. If you
take a long term policy, then the company
gives you some discount which we will see later. There is
no room rent restriction, sir. Actually, there is no
room rent. The term for camping procedures is
domiciliary
hospitalization, that is also covered.
Hospitalization is done if the patient is not well enough to be taken to the
hospital, then also one will be done.
Refill benefit is available here for one to two
years for unrelated illness only.
Expenses of 90 days before and 18 days after are
covered. Emergency road ambulance will actually be given in this policy.
Whatever actual expenses will be incurred will be given. There is
no restriction in UPTU.
Air ambulance is also covered. There is up to
five lakh rupees per rider. Modern treatment or
it is also called special treatments.
If the policy is of 10 lakhs
then 50% will be given, if the policy is of 50% of the
submission then 100% will be given,
we will talk about that later, Ayush treatment
is covered, you always have some unique benefits
available which are called more option
benefit, so here three more option benefits
are available, first is more cover, so
with your existing insurance
you can add on a little more cover, by
paying a little nominal premium, if we do more
option benefit then
you get more time, along with more time you will be
given a policy of 13 months for 12 months
and if you have a policy of 2 years then it will be
counted as 26 months, so two months
additional will be given to you, so the coverage you have will
last for a long time and if we
talk about global, then here emergency
hospitalization, if you are outside India then
your hospital will be covered there too and if there is
plantation then that will also be covered and now
200%  The maximum limit is Rs 50 lakh. The
most attractive feature of this plan, which I would like to mention, is the
numerous discounts.
15 discounts are available. So, let
us see one by one what all these 15 discounts are.
So, the first one is the voluntary co-payment
discount. If you turn off co-payment
in this policy, then you get a discount of
10% on your premium. Second, there is a policy
discount and if you turn off the
long term policy, which means a
policy of 2.2 years or 3 years, then also you are
given a 10% discount. The third discount in Van Gogh
is the family discount. If
you take a multi-individual policy, then
you get a family discount. Where
you are adding more than 200 members
in the policy, then there is a family discount of
10%. If you continue the policy, then
basically your loyalty discount is
2.5%. You are given a discount at the
time of renewal. The fifth
discount is the prime discount. Prime discount
means if you are an existing customer, an
employee of the Reliance Group, or a
shareholder of the Reliance Group.  Even if you are a holder, you will be given a
discount. 10% online discount on your premium.
If you buy the policy online without any
other assistance, there is a
10% discount. Seventh girl child
discount. This is the first time in Sona Health
Insurance. If you are insuring a girl child
in the policy, then
you will be given an additional 5% discount. 8th
discount is BMI discount, meaning if
your BMI is good and within the range, then
discount will be given. If it is above the range, then
loading will be levied. You must have heard the concept of loading.
In health insurance, if
your BMI deviates from the standard, then
loading is levied. The good thing here is that
if it is less than the standard or within the range, then
no loading is levied.
Early bird discount. Early bird discount
means if you have a policy running somewhere else
and within 3 years you
port the policy to them and
you are less than 50 years old, then also you are
given a discount. In this 5% credit score
discount, I had told you about your
financial fitness and physical fitness, so
we have talked about the discount. Credit source,
credit score discount link is your
financial  Along with fitness, if your
credit score is good then you will get a discount.
If your credit score is not good
then loading will also be levied. Which current is close?
Your discount: If you have more than one
health insurance policy and you
disclose them, then you will get a 2.5%
discount. Female propose
discount: If the proposer of the policy is
female, then you will be given a 5% discount.
Vaccination discount: If you have taken the Covid-19
vaccination or the Namo Kovid
vaccine, then there is a 2.5% discount.
Your stay healthy discount: If you
remain active and your health checkup results are good, then
10% discount is given.
Annual free zone wise discount: D.
Basically, if you are in the lower zone or zone B, then
you are given a 20% discount.
So, after adding all the discounts here, the
maximum discount that you will be given will be
35%. Now we will talk about advance,
as I told you,
what are those I don't call in the 15 useful add-ons policy,
so first I don't call is unlimited
cover, it means consumable cover, so whatever
your  The consumable cost will be paid
and along with this
you will also be given unlimited restore benefit. Within this rider,
within the same rider, under the limitless cover,
your consumables are also being covered and
unlimited restore benefit is being given for
related and unrelated in less both. Then there is
Smart Protector, so Smart Protector
is basically a super charge in which your additional
time shot will be given 30% and 30% every
year on renewal. So basically the concept of bonus
is the concept of additional premium.
Along with this, the second benefit in Smart Protector
is air ambulance cover because it will be covered
up to Rs 5 lakh. So
in case of medical evacuation, you can use it. If we
talk about OPD cover, then OPT
cover is also available as a rider. Here
you have the option of OPD available.
OPT coverage from Rs 10,000 to Rs 50,000
is available. So here two plans are available, one
plan is Rs 5 lakh.  The
plan is given for short from Rs. 10 lakh to Rs. 10 lakh and
for short above Rs. 5 lakh, in Rs. 10 lakh, the
OPD consultation is available to you with 10 super specialists. The
word for diagnostic test is
your medicine, that is 35% of the OPD
limit, whatever you take, if the
OPD limit is 10,000 then 35% is 3500, only that can be
reversed and here at the time of Rs. 5 lakh
10 lakh, the maximum OPD limit is 20,000.
Similarly, if you come in Plan B
above Rs. 10 lakh, then OPD consultation with medical
practices is covered.
You can take up to 35% of your diagnostic test, drugs, medicines.
Dental treatment and related
diagnostic test or prescription
cost will also be covered. Plan B and surgical
treatments are covered. The OPD surgical
treatments are covered. OPD
limits are 25,000 to 250,000, you can choose.
Next is medical  Care Equipment
Cover: Here, for your durable medical
equipment, you will be given 5% off time shot, which means a
maximum of ₹5 lakh and for small
medical equipment, you will be given 1% off time shot,
maximum Rs 20,000. Double cover: If
you want 2X cover from day one, you have
seen the concept of 2X cover in some policies,
so here also 2X cover comes at an additional
cost. If you want 100% cover and cover in all, then you
can opt for a double cover rider.
Next is home care treatment. If you
want treatment at home, then you
can opt for within some limits.
For that also you will have to pay an additional premium.
Next is the pre-existing waiting
period. The existing
waiting period for free existing conditions is 36 months. If you
want to make it 24 months or 48 months,
that is possible or 12 months, then 12
months and 24 months  If you opt for
48 months, you will have to pay the traditional premium. If you opt for 48 months,
you will get a discount. This means that if you do not have any free existing condition, then you can opt for
48 months and
you will get a discount.
You can also reduce your policy waiting period
from 24 months to 12 months. You can opt for
voluntary aggregable and deductible in some additional frames,
so that the
premium is reduced. Deductible options are
available, from Rs. 10,000 to Rs. 12,
in this you are
given a discount in the premium. Reduction and room
rent: If you want to modify your room rent,
right now you have no room
rent, you have other rooms, and you want to change it and take a single
private one room or a shared room on twin
sharing basis, then the
premium will reduce accordingly and you will get a
discount. So, so many choices are
available, so much flexibility
is available, so you
can choose and pick as per your convenience.  What you
need and what you don't need, now let's talk about
waiting periods, so the waiting period is the
standard waiting period in just one policy,
your initial waiting period is 30 days, Pacific exclusions
waiting period is 24, existing waiting
period is 36 months, next is mother and
child care benefit, so here it is clear from the name itself
that this is maternity cover, so
maternity expenses are covered after 1 year, two years
depends on which plan you will choose, the
limit is 1 lakh and 2 lakh,
normal end size, along with this,
if there is cover for newborn baby and vaccination, then up to one
lakh rupees, so this benefit will be given only
when you will do a policy of 3 years,
if you need maternity
benefit, you can take it, so let's talk about the
premium, here I have
calculated the premium for zone 1, so
in zone 1 I have given family two plus two age policy, 44, 38, 18
and 13 and 10 lakhs  I have taken 10 plus plan but
I have not added any rider, I have taken it without rider, just to
show you the
exact premium, you can add rider as per
your wish, so here the premium for 1 year
is 20676 and here the
two discounts that are applicable are
10% online discount because I was
calculating it online and 5% girl child
discount because in this policy when we are
taking a family of two plus two, then this girl
child is also there, so by applying 15% discount here the
premium will be 20676, you
can see as per your wish, how much your premium will be as per
your wish
and as per your rider, as per your
discount application, so
this is all about Reliance Health
Infinity plan, if you have any questions,
give any feedback, if you want to add on anything,
please take it in the comment section and
if you want to buy our health insurance,
our team has given
WhatsApp number, email ID and Google form
link is also available in the description, you
can contact us if you like the video  If you found it
useful, you
can share it with your friends and family.
A quick reminder before leaving. If
you have not yet subscribed to our channel, then
subscribe and you get the
right information. If you are right, we will meet
soon in the next video
with more information. Thank you so much. If you
want to discuss
these